#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/khyati-vashi-b96103a3 (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Full-Stack Development Agile Systems Design

#### Certifications

Scrum Master Certified (SMC)
OCJP

# Khyati Vashi

Full-Stack Developer at Visa, Inc Singapore

## Summary

Full stack developer with 8+ years experience in application design, development & implementation.

Currently involved in the design and development efforts for rewriting legacy applications and processes. This comprises of analysis, planning and choosing the right technology stack for the rewrite efforts for building efficient processes.

Primarily working on developing front-end & back-end applications using various open source technologies like Spring MVC, Ext JS, Angular JS, MyBatis, Docker etc.

Passionate about learning new technologies, leading technical redesign efforts & exploring the world of programming.

# Experience

Visa

4 years 3 months

Staff Software Engineer

October 2018 - Present (2 years 6 months)

Singapore

Currently working on the front-end & back-end rewrite efforts at Visa for migrating the legacy

applications/processes to an open source based solution.

Responsible for the architecture, planning, design and implementation of micro service based

solutions in an agile fashion for tightly coupled legacy code.

Work on POCs and test the solution for efficiency, performance before it's implemented at a wider

level.

Develop/program new functionality and features in line with functional specifications and business requirements.

Senior Software Engineer
January 2017 - October 2018 (1 year 10 months)

Page 1 of 2

#### Singapore

Migrated the legacy UI which was in Mainframe to new UI using Ext JS, Node JS and Angular.

Develop/program new functionality and features in line with functional specifications and business requirements.

Work with the application team to create requirements for the legacy systems rewrite.

Oracle in Financial Services
Staff Consultant
August 2014 - December 2016 (2 years 5 months)

Primarily worked as an Agile Java developer, developing new functionalities for various upstream applications & exposing them using REST Webservices. Involved in UI development for a trading application for an esteemed bank using Spring, Hibernate and SmartGWT for faster response times.

Tata Consultancy Services
Systems Engineer
March 2012 - August 2014 (2 years 6 months)
Mumbai

Worked as a Java Developer for 2.5 years for building the new taxation reform system GST (Goods & Services Taxation).

Proficient in developing new functionalities in Spring 3.0 & JPA. Build automation through Maven.

## Education

University of Mumbai
Bachelor's degree, Information Technology · (2007 - 2011)